standardchartered.com.sg 2018-12-13

# Privacy - Standard Chartered Singapore

    Privacy Statement
    Privacy Statement (Corporate and Institutional Clients)

  * This Privacy Statement relates to the collection, use and disclosure of personal data, including special or sensitive personal data, by any member of the Standard Chartered Group (“SCB”, “we” or “our”). Personal Data is information relating to an individual (“you” or “your”).

The Data Controller of your personal data is the SCB entity you have or may have a relationship with or with whom an account is maintained that you are a security provider for. Our Head Office functions may also be the controller of your personal data.

Personal Data comprises all the details SCB holds or collects about you, directly or indirectly, your transactions, transactions you effect, financial information, interactions and dealings with SCB, including information received from third parties, the public domain, collected through use of our website, cookies, and our electronic banking services.

If you have or are party to more than one account with SCB, or to a Corporate and Institutional Banking relationship, we will link all your Personal Data to enable us to have an overall picture of your relationship with us.

If you do not provide us with personal data we need to meet our legal and regulatory obligations or to enter into an agreement with you we may not be able to provide you with the products or services you have requested.

**PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE MAY PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

To enable us to fulfil the contract between us for the services you have requested, we need to process your Personal Data for purposes including the following:

    * processing applications for products and services, effecting payments, transactions and completing instructions or requests;
    * providing products and services (including electronic banking service);
    * assessing suitability for products and services;
    * credit assessment, including conducting credit checks and setting credit limits;
    * operational purposes; 
    * statistical purposes;
    * establishment, continuation and management of banking relationships and account;
    * surveillance of premises and ATMs.

For some purposes in connection with the service you have requested, we have a legal or regulatory obligation to process your personal data. These purposes include:

    * the prevention, detection, investigation and prosecution of crime in any jurisdiction (including, without limitation, money laundering, terrorism, fraud and other financial crime);
    * identity verification, government sanctions screening and due diligence checks;
    * to comply with: local or foreign law, regulations, directives, judgments or court orders, government sanctions or embargoes, reporting requirements under financial transactions legislation, and demands of any authority, regulator, tribunal, enforcement agency, or exchange body.

We may also process your personal data in line with any voluntary codes; to effect agreements between any member of the Standard Chartered Group and any authority, regulator, or enforcement agency; to comply with policies (including the Standard Chartered Group’s policies) and good practice standards where it is in our legitimate interest to do so.

We may also process your personal data where it is in our legitimate interests to seek professional advice, including, in connection with any legal proceedings (including any prospective legal proceedings), for obtaining legal advice or for establishing, exercising or defending legal rights.

<back to top>

**TO WHOM WE MAY DISCLOSE PERSONAL DATA**

Any member of SCB, including our officers, employees, agents and advisers, may disclose your Personal Data to any of the following parties for any of the purposes specified above:

    * any member of the Standard Chartered Group anywhere in the world, including any officer, employee, agent or director;
    * professional advisers (including auditors), third party service providers, agents or independent contractors providing services to support SCB’s business;
    * our business alliance partners who may provide their product or service to you;
    * a merchant or a member of a card association where the disclosure is in connection with use of a card;
    * upon your death or mental incapacity, your legal representative and their legal advisers, and a member of your immediate family for the purpose of allowing him/her to make payment on your account;
    * any security provider or any person authorised to operate your account and to act on your behalf in giving instructions, to perform any other acts under our banking agreement or use any product;
    * any person to whom disclosure is allowed or required by local or foreign law, regulation or any other applicable instrument;
    * any court, tribunal, regulator, enforcement agency, exchange body, tax authority, or any other authority (including any authority investigating an offence) or their agents;
    * any debt collection agency, credit bureau or credit reference agency, rating agency correspondents, insurer or insurance broker, direct or indirect provider of credit protection and fraud prevention agencies;
    * any financial institution to conduct credit checks, anti-money laundering related checks, for fraud prevention and detection of crime purposes;
    * anyone we consider necessary to facilitate requests for services or applications for products with any member of the Standard Chartered Group;
    * anyone we consider necessary in order to provide services in connection with a product;
    * enabling an actual or potential assignee of all or any part of the business and/or asset of the Standard Chartered Group or participant or sub-participant of our rights in respect of any product agreement, to evaluate the transaction intended to be the subject of the assignment, participation or sub-participation;

located in any jurisdiction.

<back to top>

**SECURITY**

Personal data may be transferred to, or stored at, a location outside of your country of residence, which may not have data protection law. The security of your personal data is important to us. SCB has technical and organisational security measures in place to safeguard your personal data. When using external service providers, we require that they adhere to security standards mandated by SCB. We may do this through contractual provisions, including any approved by a privacy regulator, and oversight of the service provider. Regardless of where personal data is transferred, we take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that personal data is kept securely.

You should be aware that the Internet is not a secure form of communication and you must not send us any personal data over the Internet as this carries with it risks including the risk of access and interference by unauthorised third parties. Information passing over the Internet may be transmitted internationally (even when sender and recipient are located in the same country) via countries with weaker privacy and data protection laws than in your country of residence.

<back to top>

**OTHER TERMS AND CONDITIONS**

There may be specific terms and conditions in our banking and product agreements that govern the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Data. Such other terms and conditions must be read in conjunctions with this Privacy Statement.

<back to top>

**RETENTION**

We retain your Personal Data in line with our legal and regulatory obligations and for business and operational purposes. In the majority of cases this will be for seven years from the end of your relationship with us.

<back to top>

**AUTOMATED DECISIONS AND PROFILING**

We will use profiling, including behavioural analysis, to assist us to provide you with better services, to make decisions and to prevent money laundering, terrorism, fraud and other financial crime, for example using profiling will help us to try and detect whether use of your credit card may be fraudulent. If any profiling will result in an automated decision relating to you, we will let you know and you will have the right to discuss the decision with us.

<back to top>

**MARKETING**

We will use your personal data: 

    * to conduct market research and surveys with the aim of improving our products and services;
    * for marketing purposes, promotional events, competitions and lucky draws;

We process your personal data for these purposes because it is in the interest of our business to do so with the intention of improving our products and services and generating business. We will not send you marketing material if you have specifically asked us not to do so. You have the right to opt out of receiving marketing material at any time. To do so please contact your branch or relationship manager.

Clients with Relationship Managers, such as Private Banking and Priority clients of SCB, may from time to time be contacted by their relationship manager to discuss products and services designed to suit their investment objectives and/or interests.

If you change your mind and ask us not to send you marketing material or other promotional or research material you have subscribed to receive, we will need to retain a record that you have asked us not to do so to ensure that you do not receive anything further.

<back to top>

**MONITORING**

To the extent permitted by law, we may record and monitor your electronic communications with us to ensure compliance with our legal and regulatory obligations and internal policies for the purposes outlined above.

<back to top>

**YOUR RIGHTS**

    * Access

Subject to applicable law, regulations and/or banking industry guidelines, you may have the right to request a copy of the Personal Data processed in relation to you. SCB may be allowed by law to charge a fee for this.

    * Correction

You can request at any time that we correct your personal data at your branch or through your relationship manager.

    * Erasure

In some circumstances you have the right to ask us to delete your personal data, for example if we no longer have a valid reason to process it.

    * Object

In some circumstances you may have the right to object to how we process your personal data but this does not mean you can decide or choose how we process your personal data other than in relation to marketing. If you have any concerns about how we process your personal data, please discuss this at your branch or with your Relationship Manager. We may not be able to offer you services if you do not want us to process the personal data we consider it necessary to process to provide the services.

    * Restriction

In some circumstances you may have the right to restrict how your personal data is processed.

    * Portability

In some circumstances you may have the right to request the personal data you have given to us in a machine readable format. You can already do this through on line banking in relation to your banking transactions.

<back to top>

**CONTACTING US**

**By telephone:**

Personal Banking |  1800 747 7000 (24-hour)  
(65) 6747 7000 (24-hour) if calling from overseas   
---|---  
Priority Banking |  1800 846 8000 (24-hour)  
(65) 6846 8000 (24-hour) if calling from overseas   
Private Banking |  Please contact your Relationship Manager   
Business Banking |  1800 743 3000 (Mon to Fri – 9:00am to 6:00pm)  
(65) 6743 3000 (Mon to Fri – 9:00am to 6:00pm) if calling from overseas   
  
**By Mail:**

The Data Privacy Officer  
Standard Chartered Bank (Singapore) Limited  
8 Marina Boulevard #27-01  
Marina Bay Financial Centre  
Singapore 018981 

**COMPLAINTS**

If you have a complaint in relation to the processing of your personal data and you are not happy with the way we deal with it, please discuss this at your branch or with your Relationship Manager, or contact the Data Privacy Officer. You also have the right to complain to the data protection authority, if one exists, in the country where you have a relationship with the Bank, or if your relationship is with SCB outside of the European Union but you are located there, the UK Information Commissioner. Details can be provided by emailing [Singapore.Privacy@sc.com](mailto:Singapore.Privacy@sc.com)

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time and you are advised to visit this site regularly to check for any amendments. This policy was last updated on 25 May 2018.

**LINKED WEBSITES**

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites where our online advertisements are displayed or to linked third-party websites which we do not operate or control.

<back to top>

  * This Privacy Statement relates to the collection, use and disclosure of personal data, including special or sensitive personal data, by any member of the Standard Chartered Group (“SCB”, “we” or “our”). In this Privacy Statement and related contractual terms and policy documents “Personal Information” or “Personal data” is information relating to an individual (“you” or “your”) and “data subject” has the same meaning as “individual”.

Personal data we collect in respect of Corporate and Institutional Banking, Global Banking and Commercial Banking (collectively “Corporate and Institutional Banking”) and Business Banking relationships is primarily limited to the information on Directors and Officers, direct and indirect beneficial owners and authorised persons we need to enable us to meet our due diligence obligations, signatory details and contact information of individuals we interact with to enable the provision of services to a Corporate and Institutional Banking or Business Banking entity.

The Data Controller of your personal data is the SCB entity you have a relationship with. Our Head Office functions may also be the controller of your personal data.

Personal data comprises all the details SCB holds or collects about you, directly or indirectly, your transactions, transactions you effect, financial information, interactions and dealings with SCB, including information received from third parties, the public domain, collected through use of our website, cookies, and our electronic banking services.

If you have or are party to more than one account with SCB, or to a Private or Retail Banking relationship, we will link all your Personal data to enable us to have an overall picture of your relationship with us.

**PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE MAY PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We process Personal data where it is in our legitimate interests to do so to enable us to fulfil the contract between us and the Corporate and Institutional Banking entity or Business Banking entity for the services requested, including the following:

    * processing applications for products and services, effecting payments, transactions and completing instructions or requests;
    * providing products and services (including electronic banking service);
    * assessing suitability for products and services;
    * credit assessment, including conducting credit checks and setting credit limits; 
    * operational purposes;
    * establishment, continuation and management of banking relationships and accounts; and 
    * surveillance of premises

For some purposes in connection with the service requested, we have a legal or regulatory obligation to process your personal data. These purposes include:

    * the prevention, detection, investigation and prosecution of crime in any jurisdiction (including, without limitation, money laundering, terrorism, fraud and other financial crime);
    * identity verification, government sanctions screening and due diligence checks; and
    * to comply with: local or foreign law, regulations, directives, judgments or court orders, government sanctions or embargoes, reporting requirements under financial transactions legislation, and demands of any authority, regulator, tribunal, enforcement agency, or exchange body.

We may also process your personal data in line with any voluntary codes; to effect agreements between SCB and any authority, regulator, or enforcement agency; to comply with policies (including the Standard Chartered Group’s policies) and good practice standards where it is in our legitimate interest to do so.

Personal data is also processed where it is in our legitimate interests to seek professional advice, including, in connection with any legal proceedings (including any prospective legal proceedings), for obtaining legal advice or for establishing, exercising or defending legal rights.

<back to top>

**TO WHOM WE MAY DISCLOSE PERSONAL DATA**

Any member of SCB, including our officers, employees, agents, advisers and directors, may disclose your Personal data to any of the following parties for any of the purposes specified above:

    * any other member of SCB anywhere in the world, including any officer, employee, agent, advisor or director;
    * professional advisers (including auditors), third party service providers, agents or independent contractors providing services to support SCB’s business;
    * any person to whom disclosure is allowed or required by local or foreign law, regulation or any other applicable instrument;
    * any court, tribunal, regulator, enforcement agency, exchange body, tax authority, or any other authority (including any authority investigating an offence) or their agents;
    * any financial institution to conduct credit checks, anti-money laundering related checks, for fraud prevention and detection of crime purposes;
    * anyone we consider necessary to facilitate requests for services or applications for products with any member of SCB;
    * anyone we consider necessary in order to provide services in connection with a product;
    * any actual or potential (a) assignee of all or any part of the business and/or asset of the Standard Chartered Group or (b) participant or sub-participant of our rights in respect of any product agreement, in order to evaluate the transaction intended to be the subject of the assignment, participation or sub-participation (or any officer, employee, agent or adviser of any of these parties);

located in any jurisdiction.

<back to top>

**SECURITY**

Personal data may be transferred to, or stored at, a location outside of your country of residence, which may not have data protection law. The security of your personal data is important to us. SCB has technical and organisational security measures in place to safeguard your personal data. When using external service providers, we require that they adhere to security standards mandated by SCB. We may do this through contractual provisions, including any approved by a privacy regulator, and oversight of the service provider. Regardless of where personal data is transferred, we take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that personal data is kept securely.

You should be aware that the Internet is not a secure form of communication and you must not send us any personal data over the Internet as this carries with it risks including the risk of access and interference by unauthorised third parties. Information passing over the Internet may be transmitted internationally (even when sender and recipient are located in the same country) via countries with weaker privacy and data protection laws than in your country of residence.

<back to top>

**OTHER TERMS AND CONDITIONS**

There may be specific terms and conditions in our banking and product agreements that govern the collection, use and disclosure of your personal data. Such other terms and conditions must be read in conjunctions with this Privacy Statement.

<back to top>

**RETENTION**

We retain your Personal data in line with our legal and regulatory obligations and for business and operational purposes. In the majority of cases this will be for seven years from the end of your relationship with us. 

<back to top>

**MARKETING**

We will use your business contact data: 

    * to conduct market research and surveys with the aim of improving our products and services to Corporate and Institutional Banking clients or Business Banking clients;
    * to market our products to Corporate and Institutional Banking clients or Business Banking clients and for promotional events.

We process your personal data for these purposes because it is in the interest of our business to do so with the intention of improving our products and services and generating business. We will not send you marketing material if you have specifically asked us not to do so. You have the right to opt out of receiving marketing material on behalf of the Corporate or and Institutional Banking entity or Business Banking entity that you represent at any time. To do so please contact your relationship manager. 

If you change your mind and ask us not to send you marketing material or other promotional or research material you have subscribed to receive, we will need to retain a record that you have asked us not to do so to ensure that you do not receive anything further.

<back to top>

**MONITORING**

To the extent permitted by law, we may record and monitor your electronic communications with us to ensure compliance with our legal and regulatory obligations and internal policies for the purposes outlined above. 

<back to top>

**YOUR RIGHTS**

• Access  
Subject to applicable law, regulations and/or banking industry guidelines, you may have the right to request a copy of the Personal data processed in relation to you. SCB may be allowed by law to charge a fee for this.

• Correction  
You can request at any time that we correct your personal data at your branch or through your relationship manager.

• Erasure  
In some circumstances you have the right to ask us to delete your personal data, for example if we no longer have a valid reason to process it.

• Object  
In some circumstances you may have the right to object to how we process your personal data but this does not mean you can decide or choose how we process your personal data other than in relation to marketing. If you have any concerns about how we process your personal data, please discuss this with your Relationship Manager. We may not be able to offer the services if you do not want us to process the personal data we consider it necessary to provide the services.

• Restriction  
In some circumstances you may have the right to restrict how your personal data is processed. 

<back to top>

**CONTACTING US**

**By telephone:**

Please contact your Relationship Manager or our Client Services Group at (65) 6876 0888. For Business Banking, please call 1800 743 3000. 

**By Mail:**

The Data Privacy Officer  
c\o Standard Chartered Bank (Singapore) Limited  
8 Marina Boulevard #27-01  
Marina Bay Financial Centre  
Singapore 018981 

**COMPLAINTS**

If you have a complaint in relation to the processing of your personal data and you are not happy with the way we deal with it, please discuss this with your Relationship Manager, or contact the Data Privacy Officer.

You also have the right to complain to the data protection authority, if one exists, in the country where you have a relationship with the Bank. Details can be provided by emailing [Singapore.Privacy@sc.com](mailto:Singapore.Privacy@sc.com)

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time and you are advised to visit this site regularly to check for any amendments. This policy was last updated on 7 June 2018.

**LINKED WEBSITES**

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites where our online advertisements are displayed or to linked third-party websites which we do not operate or control.

<back to top>

  * Standard Chartered Bank (Singapore) Limited respects your privacy and we are committed to keeping your personal information and other data confidential and secure.

    1. **When does this Website Privacy Statement apply?**

This Website Privacy Statement explains the approach taken by Standard Chartered Bank (Singapore) Limited, and the members of the Standard Chartered Group ("SCB Group", "we" or "us") toward the personal information and data that we collect about you ("Your Information") when you visit this Website, electronically respond to our online advertisements or when you send us communications via any computer, mobile or other similar electronic devices ("Device"). It does not apply to information we collect in other ways e.g. when you are dealing with our staff in a branch or over the telephone. In these cases, there may be other privacy statements and terms and conditions that are applicable.

This Website Privacy Statement is limited to information and data collected on this Website, our online advertisements and electronic communications. Our Website Privacy Statement does not apply when you leave our Website, including third-party websites where our online advertisements are displayed or links to third-party websites which we do not operate or control. Please read the privacy statements and terms and conditions of these third-party websites and decide whether they satisfactorily protect your rights.

    2. **You consent to our use of Your Information and Cookies**

By using this Website, responding to our online advertisements and/or providing Your Information you consent to: (a) our use of Cookies (see section 3(a) below) and our use of Your Information as described in this Website Privacy Statement; and (b) the terms and conditions of this Website Privacy Statement. If you do not consent then please do not proceed further and do not provide Your Information.

    3. **What information do we collect about you?**

The Website is designed to use Cookies to collect information about how people use the Website (see _Use of Cookies_ ) and in some parts of our Website, we specifically ask for Your Information (see _Online Forms_ and _Job Applicants_ ). Otherwise, you can use the Website without providing Your Information.

      1. **Use of Cookies**

Cookies are small data files which are placed on your Device when you visit certain parts of our Website or click on our online advertisements. Cookies and similar technologies are used to identify your Device for the following purposes:-

        1. **Strictly necessary cookies.** These essential cookies are set throughout our Website and are required for the operation of our Website to: 
          * allow our web server to determine whether the cookies setting on your web browser has been enabled or disabled. This allows us to know whether data can be collected from your web browser;
          * temporarily allow you to carry information between pages of our Website to avoid having to re-enter that information;
          * temporarily identify your Device after you have logged in to a secure page on our Website so that our web server can maintain a dialogue with your web browser in order for you to carry out certain activities.
        2. **Analytical/performance cookies.** These are used to help us improve our Website by: 
          * tracking your visits to our Website and recognising your web browser when you are a repeat visitor so that we can gather statistics on new and repeat visitors to evaluate site effectiveness.
        3. **Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognise you when you return to our Website. This enables us to: 
          * to remember the choices you make (such as your user name, language and region) so you do not have to re-enter that information when you return to the Website;
          * personalise our Website content for you.
        4. **Targeting / advertising cookies.** These cookies record your visit to our Website, your response to our online advertisements, track the pages you have visited and the website links you have followed. We use this information to: 
          * make our Website more relevant to your interests based on your past visits to our Website;
          * tailor our online advertisements or offers on our Website or third-party websites which are most likely to interest you;
          * evaluate the effectiveness of our online marketing and advertising campaigns.

The above cookies may be placed on your Device by us or by third parties on our behalf (for example, advertising service providers like Google and DoubleClick and other service providers for web analytics).

Most web browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can choose to 'not accept' cookies by changing the settings on your web browser but if you block all cookies, including strictly necessary cookies, you may find that certain features on our Website will not work properly.

You can opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting Google's Ad Settings and DoubleClick's use of cookies by visiting the DoubleClick opt-out page.

      2. **Online Forms**

There are sections of the Website where we ask for personal information, for example, when you complete online forms to submit an enquiry, apply for a particular product or service or if you register to use our secure online services such as Online Banking. Please ensure you also read any applicable Terms and Conditions for these products and services.

      3. **Job Applicants**

Personal information provided on our Website in connection with an application for employment will be used to determine your suitability for a position with the SCB Group and, if applicable, your terms of employment or engagement. Your Information may also be used to monitor our recruitment initiatives and equal opportunities policies. Applicant details may be disclosed to third parties to verify or obtain additional information including education institutions, current/previous employers and credit reference agencies. Credit reference agencies record these searches and you can contact us to find out which agencies we used. Unsuccessful applications may be retained to match your skills to future job opportunities. These are usually retained for up for 12 months but please let us know if you do not wish us to retain Your Information for this purpose.

      4. **Electronic Communications**

If you contact us via email, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

    4. **How we use Your Information**

We will always treat Your Information as confidential. We will use good practices to keep it secure and will otherwise abide by the relevant data protection and privacy laws.

      1. **Using Your Information - Purposes**

If you provide Your Information on the Website in relation to any products and services from the Bank, or send us an electronic communication, we will use Your Information for the purposes ("Purposes") of providing and operating the product or service you request or responding to your electronic communication and for other related purposes that may include: 
        * following up on any product or service application which you have shown interest in;
        * updating our records about you;
        * understanding your financial needs;
        * conducting credit checks and assisting other financial institutions to conduct credit checks;
        * crime or fraud detection, prevention and prosecution;
        * debt collection;
        * complying with laws or regulations;
        * research and statistical analysis with the aim of improving our products and services;
        * handling queries and complaints.

Please ensure you also read the Terms and Conditions applicable to these products and services.

      2. **Marketing**

We generally do not use Your Information collected on this Website for marketing purposes but if you apply for products and services on the Website, Your Information may be used to inform you about other related products and services of SCB Group that may be of interest.  
If you do not wish to be contacted in this way please call our 24-hour Phone Banking team. 

      3. **Disclosing Your Information**

When using Your Information for the Purposes we may need to disclose it to more than one company within the SCB Group and to our agents, advisors and third party service providers ("Other Parties"). When this happens we will require the Other Parties to handle Your Information using the same level of care that we apply. We will also require them to only use Your Information according to our instructions and directions.

If the Other Parties are overseas Your Information may be sent to another country including countries with weaker privacy and data protection laws than in your country of residence. We will not otherwise disclose Your Information to third parties unless we have your permission or we are under a legal or similar obligation.

This means, by way of example, that Your Information may be disclosed to: 
        * regulators, supervisors, governments or quasi-governmental authorities in countries where we, our agents, advisors or third party service providers have a presence;
        * agents, advisors or third party service providers under a duty of confidentiality to the SCB Group;
        * credit reference, debt collection, anti-money laundering and fraud prevention agencies (where necessary for the Purposes).
      4. **Retaining Your Information**

We will retain Your Information for as long as the Purpose for which we collected it continues. It is then destroyed unless further retention is required to satisfy a legal, regulatory or accounting requirement or to protect our interests.

    5. **Privacy, security and communications using the Internet**

      1. The Internet is not a secure form of communication and sending and receiving information over the Internet carries with it risks including the risk of access and interference by unauthorized third parties. It is your responsibility to maintain the secrecy of any user ID and login password you hold.
      2. Information passing over the Internet may be transmitted internationally (even when sender and recipient are located in the same country) via countries with weaker privacy and data protection laws than in your country of residence. As a result, we do not accept responsibility or liability for the confidentiality, security or integrity of Your Information in connection with its transmission over the Internet.
      3. In order to maintain the security of our systems, protect our staff, record transactions, and, in certain circumstances, to prevent and detect crime or unauthorised activities, we reserve the right to monitor all Internet communications including web and email traffic into and out of our domains.
    6. **Changes to our Website Privacy Statement**

We update our Website Privacy Statement from time to time and ask that you regularly check this Website to make sure you are familiar with the most recent version.

This Website Privacy Statement was last updated on 15 November 2013.

COPYRIGHT©STANDARD CHARTERED BANK 2013. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. 

Standard Chartered Bank (the “Bank”) is committed to maintaining a culture of the highest ethics and integrity, and in compliance with all applicable law, regulation and internal policy. As part of this commitment, the Bank has a ‘Speaking Up’ programme through which genuine concerns in this regard can be raised. Members of the public can securely raise Speaking Up concerns through this hyperlink, which is hosted on behalf of the Bank by a third party ‘InTouch’. Examples of concerns that can be raised through this website are concerns that relate to accounting, internal accounting controls or auditing matters and concerns relating to bribery or banking and financial crime. Concerns received will be forwarded to the Bank’s investigations team for review. Complaints relating to SCB banking services should not be raised through this site in the first instance, but through the SCB branch network, contact centres, Relationship Managers or the ‘Contact Us’ webpage.

Please note that this hyperlink will bring to you to another website on the Internet, which is operated by InTouch, an independent company appointed by the Bank to support its Speaking Up programme. Please be mindful that when you click on the link and open a new window in your browser, you will be subject to the additional terms of use of the website that you are going to visit.
